## Charles Fyfe

☑ ch@rles.uno

• charles.uno

**J** 651-269-9245

• Minneapolis

## **Summary**

Ten years automation and analysis in Python. Fluent in Linux and shell scripting. Recent emphasis on CI/CD/CT infrastructure with Jenkins, Docker, and REST APIs. Comfortable mentoring interns, onboarding employees, and creating educational materials for new technologies.

## Experience -

Cray Inc: Intern  $\rightarrow$  Test Engineer  $\rightarrow$  DevOps Engineer

2014-Present

- Wrote a **Groovy** pipeline to build, test, and distribute RPMs in support of 100+ engineers.
- Illustrated pipeline usage with an annotated end-to-end example: a REST API written in Go, wrapped in a Docker container, and deployed to Kubernetes via Ansible.
- Rolled out a **Continuous Testing** solution for the Shasta product line. Secured VP buy-in, communicated requirements to dozens of product groups, and followed up on concerns.
- Designed a framework to execute nightly tests on live mainframes. Ingested results into an
  ELK database. Interfaced with Slack and Jira APIs to notify product owners of failures.
- Crawled the **Jenkins REST API** to monitor deployments of 6 product streams across 27 mainframes. Aggregated metrics onto a **CGI** dashboard viewed 100+ times daily.
- Implemented a **Python** API for access and analysis of mainframe system logs. Parsed terabytes of text to diagnose hardware failures on a \$70 million customer installation.
- Mentored two interns, both of whom were awarded extensions. Prepared and presented educational materials to onboard dozens of new employees.

University of Minnesota: Teaching Assistant  $\rightarrow$  Research Assistant 2009–2016

- Benchmarked and optimized a wave simulation in parallel Fortran. Implemented a Python harness to configure, compile, and launch hundreds of simulations in parallel.
- Analyzed hundreds of gigabytes of data with **Numpy** to isolate novel patterns.
- Led laboratory exercises and tutored at-risk students individually. Coordinated between professors, graduate teaching assistants, and undergraduate tutors as Head TA.

## Education

University of Minnesota: PhD

2009-2016

— Space physics, Burlaga/Arctowski Medal Fellow

St Olaf College: BA

2005-2009

- Math (Distinction), Physics (Distinction), Magna Cum Laude